If you have or are thinking of taking any insurance policy of United India Car,
Bike, Taxi, Commercial Vehicle, Trucks,
Tractor
and you
want to know how this company is?
How will your experience be at the time of claims
?  Will the company pay you the claim money
or not?  How much support will you provide?  So, there
is no direct way to find out.  And to solve this problem,
I am making this video for you today.
Because in today's video I will
tell you what are the benefits of buying United India Motor
Insurance [sound of clearing throat]
policy and
why we take the decision that we will
buy United India policy only.  Along with this,
I will also tell you the disadvantages that you may face in the
claims time service if you buy a motor insurance policy from United India so
that your expectations remain
realistic.  And the matter will
not end here.  I am going to show you the
latest claims data of United India Motor Insurance.  In
which we will
try to find out
how many claims the company has settled in this stipulated time.
How much money has been paid in exchange for them and
how many complaints have been filed by the policy holders.
So if you are
buying or have already bought a motor insurance policy from United India, then
today's video is going to give you a lot of
clarity.  So without any
delay let's start the video.  There are a
total of four government insurance companies in India.
First is New India
Insurance, then United India, National
Insurance and Oriental Insurance.  But in
today's video I will specifically
talk about the advantages and disadvantages of buying a car or bike insurance policy from United India.   First of all let's
talk about the benefits.  So the
first benefit is that you will
get very cheap policies here.  When you
buy any motor insurance policy, it has
three components.  Own
Damage Premium means the money
taken for the coverage of our vehicle is
called Own Damage Premium.  Apart from this, there is
also the component of third party and GST.  The
third party and GST
component will remain the same in all companies.
But in the own damage money that the company
takes from us, some discounting
is offered by the company.  And in these
government companies including United
India Insurance, you
get more discounted prices.
Companies offer more discounts on own damage.  And
this is the first advantage of
buying a policy from United India Insurance that
you will get the policy at a very low premium.  Whether
you buy a policy for a bike, car or truck,
here up to 80-90% own damage
discount is given so that maximum number of
policy holders can get the policy.  The
second benefit is our
trust in government-backed companies.  We know
that private companies look more fancy and do
more promotion.  But
we want that company which is the safest and
also trusted.  So we have more faith and trust in any such thing, any such
business, any such company which is
backed by the Indian Government.
So this trust factor also
helps a lot in purchasing a policy from United India
and this is its second benefit.   The
third reason and benefit of buying a motor insurance policy from United India is
that it has presence even in smaller cities.
You will also find its branches in tier two and tier three cities.
Where
you can buy the policy through agent assisted or directly by visiting the branch.
The problem here is not that a private
company opened its office 6 months ago.   Since the
policies were not sold, that office was either closed
or shifted somewhere else.  You will find
permanent offices here which are years old.
Where you can go directly and
buy policies and
also discuss your claim related issues.
Friends, these are the very common
benefits due to which
we buy motor insurance policies from United India.  But
I will also
tell you in the video further about the benefits that emerge from today's latest claims data that we will review.  But first, let us
discuss some of the disadvantages that
you may face if you purchase a motor insurance policy from United India.  The
first problem you may face is the
slow process of claims.  The car meets with an accident.
We take it to the garage for repair.
After that there will be claim intimation.   The
surveyor will come and he also
takes a lot of time in submitting his report because the workload
is high and even after that, there is such a delay in getting the claim approval,
branch level approval, approval from the head office that it may take a
lot of time for you to process the claim
and what is worse is that
you do not have any option of real time tracking.
You will have to get updates from them by calling them repeatedly or visiting the branch.   The
second disadvantage is that
manual claim process is still followed within United India.
Meaning, if
you had a policy from a private insurance company
and you had to intimate a claim,
you would just have to make a phone call and the claim would be registered over the phone itself.
But
even today in United India Insurance, claim
intimation is manual.  You will have to
fill a form which will have to be
submitted to the branch of the insurance company and
after that your claim will be registered.  Now the
problem is not that we
cannot fill the claim form.  The problem is that brother,
no one has time these days.  You will have to
leave some important work and come to get all this
process done, which can cause a lot of
trouble.  The third problem is
regarding support.  If you have
purchased a motor insurance policy from United India, then
whether you
need to update the ownership, update the details
, make any corrections,
check the status of the claims or
get information about the claims,
you will get that support only by visiting the branch or
you will have to take the help of an agent.  Because no
toll free number is available directly.  This
means that it is not possible for you to
generate a service request or
get information about your claim while sitting at home or office, even then you will have to take
out time and go to the branch, only then
things will work.  The fourth disadvantage is
regarding cashless network garages.  Now brother, at the
time of claim you will have to pay the repair money first.
This is a huge loss.
Government companies do not have many network tie-
ups and even if you get them,
they can be found in private workshops.
In smaller towns and at authorised dealer
workshops, you will not be able to avail cashless claims,
which will require you to pay in advance from your pocket.
Later your claim
money will come and
I am going to show you how much time it takes in the latest claims data.
So getting a cashless claim can be
very beneficial for us.
But you may face problems in this regard in United India motor
insurance policies.
Now friends, let
me show you the
claims data of United India Motor Insurance to see
how the company is performing in terms of claims.  First of all,
this data is for the
latest three quarters of 2025-26.  That is,
from 1 April 2025 to 31 December 2025 and
when I am shooting this video, this is the
latest available data till now.  Secondly,
within this data I have included data of only motor own damage
claims.  Because you
know that third party claims in vehicles take a
lot of time and they go
through the legal process.  So the
insurance company has
no control over when the claims money was received, how much was received, or how much time it took.  Therefore,
I am going to show you here only the data of claims related to damage to our vehicle.  That
is, how many such
own damage claims has the company settled, how much money has it
paid and how much time has it taken to settle them.
And where did I get this data from
?
All these details have been taken from the public disclosure document of United India Insurance.
Now friends, first of all I will
show you the claim settlement ratio i.e.
how many own damage claims have been settled by United India per 100 claims.
So for this
we will have to look at some figures.
At the beginning of this quarter, some claims were
outstanding and some were freshly booked.   Adding
them together makes a total of 585,000 claims.
These are motor own damage claims.
Of which 415283
claims were settled by the company.  Out
of which, the company has both reputed and rejected 36700 claims.
And there are still
12,951
claims outstanding on December 31,
2025.  So, to find out the total net claims on which the decision has been
taken, we will
subtract these 12,29,000 claims from the
total claims.  So that number
comes to 455959
claims which have been disposed of and
on which decisions have been taken and out of these
how many have been settled?
In how many claims has the company given the money?  415283
If we divide this
after adjusting the outstanding, then our total claim
settlement ratio comes out to be 91%.  That means,
when a total of 100 claims were filed, if the
outstanding claims are adjusted from it, then
91 claims were approved in the 9
months.  91% of claims were approved within 9 months.
What is the reputation ratio?   Of
8.05%.  That means these claims were rejected.
Here we have
divided the rejected claims from the total disposed claims.
So the percentage came out to be 8%.  Now here at
first glance we will get to know
how good the claim settlement ratio of the company
is.  The claim settlement ratio is 91%.
But we must also look at this other shocking figure
which is the pendency ratio.
Now this claim settlement ratio of 91% has
come out when we have subtracted the pending claims from it.  The
company has
not taken any decision on 12951 claims.  That
is pending which is 22% of the total handled claims.  The
company has kept 22% claims as
outstanding.  Let
us assume for a second that there will always be so many
outstanding claims.  But if
you look at this data, at the beginning of this financial year, there were
99,9924 claims outstanding.  There
is a growth of 29% from this also.  Because currently the
number of claims that are outstanding is
approximately 13,300 claims on which the
company has not taken any decision.  That means so many
people are waiting to get their claim.
Further in this data, I will also
tell you how much time the company is taking in giving these claims.
But before that there is an
Aurent Matriculation.  There is an aurant ratio.  That
is the claims paid ratio by amount.  That is,
when the policy holder asked for a claim of ₹100,
this ratio will tell how much money the company has given out of it.  So the total amount
claimed by the policy holders
was ₹1653 crore, out of which the company has paid ₹1402 crore.
So the claims paid
ratio comes out to be ₹85%.  That means, out of ₹100
asked for, the company has given ₹85.
This deduction of ₹15
also includes rejected claims.  That means the claims which have been
completely rejected.  And if any
money has been deducted from the claim amount, any
deduction has been made, payment has been made after deducting the money
, then such deductions are also included in this 15%
amount.  Now friends, I am going to
show you a very important data about the
aging of claims.  That is, I am going to show you the
pending number of claims of the company and the money that is
pending to be paid, for how long it
is pending and what percentage of the total pending amount is that.
First of all, the aging bucket
shows how many claims
are pending for less than 3 months and how many claims are pending for
3 to 6 months.  How many
claims are pending for 6 months to one year
and how many claims are pending for more than 1 year.
And not just a claim, I will
also tell you the amount.  So the total claims
which are pending for less than 3 months are
81756 and this constitutes 63% of the total pending claims
which is a decent percentage.
But some claims are pending for 3 to 6 months
which is 2048 claims.
This is 15 1/2% of the total pending claims.  Some claims have been
pending for 6 months to a year.   The
total claims are 1538 claims and constitute
11.65% of the total outstanding claims.
And this is the most shocking data that for
more than a year, there is no
involvement of third party and court in the own damage claims that we are supposed to get for our vehicles.
12,209 such claims are pending.   This
is 9.46% of the total outstanding.  This
is a very big number.  And
you will see an even more shocking number inside the amount.  This was the
percentage that 10% of the claims were pending for more than a year.
If you
look at the amount, it is ₹357 crore which is
41% of the total outstanding amount.
It has been less than 3 months since
this has been pending.  The amount which has been pending for 3 to 6 months is
₹15 crores.
19% of the total outstanding amount.   The
claim amount pending to be paid to the company between 6 months to 1 year is
₹178 crore.  It is 20% of the total pending amount
and the amount pending for more than a year
is approximately ₹17 crore
and is 20% of the total pending amount.   That
means, out of the total amount of own damage claims that the
company had to pay, 20% amount
is pending for more than a year.  That is
quite shocking.  Now I am
also showing this to you through a bargraph chart.
The highlighted color is the
number of claims and the dull color is the
amount.  So you will see that
with time the number of claims are getting settled properly
but a lot of amount is pending.
This shows that high amount
claims, total loss claims or large own
damage claims, in which a large claim
amount has to be paid to the company, remain pending for a long time.  The
company
pays the money very late.  Because
if you look at the number of claims for more than a year, there are 12,209
pending claims.  And if you see the
amount, ₹17 crore is pending.  The amount
is 20% of the total pending amount and the number of
claims is 10% of the total pending claims.   The
data that I am showing you in today's video,
you would
never have understood with such clarity how the company is performing.
Because let us ask two men.
We accept whatever the agent convinces us to do.  But here I am going to
show you a very clear picture.
Now friends, it is time to
see the data of complaints that how many complaints have been registered by the policy holders
on the Grievance Portal of United India
?  Which category does it belong to?  How many of those
complaints have been resolved?  And how many
complaints have been decided in favor of the policy holder
and how many complaints have been decided
in favor of the insurance company.  First of all let
me give you a disclaimer.  These are the number
of complaints across all the segments.   There
is no separate classification like motor, non-motor in this.  So I will talk only about the overall complaints.
However, if we want, we can raise
motor insurance complaints in the same proportion.
But
calculating the ratio may
or may not be the right way to understand complaints.  Therefore, I will
try to explain it to you with the total complaints.  Total complaints: From
April to December 2025,
883 complaints were registered on the Grievance Portal, out
of which the maximum number of complaints were related to claims, i.e.
6869,
i.e. almost 78% complaints were related to claims only.
After that, there were a few complaints related to the
policy and the rest were minor complaints related to refund premium coverage.
If we
calculate the total complaints for 10,000
claims, then how many complaints are generated for every 10,000 claims
?  So that's
18.28.  This number is not very good
but the industry average is
above 20.  This is definitely less than that.  But I would
also like to point out that not every person who
is troubled, every police holder who is troubled, is
able to file a complaint on Graves.
He doesn't know.  So these are just the
people who knew and
complained.  Now let me show you the data that out of the
complaints made, how many
complaints were decided in favor of the company
and how many complaints were closed in favor of the policy holder.  The
total number of complaints handled
was 8803, out of which 306 complaints
were pending at the time of closing of the quarter
and the total number of complaints that have been disposed of and
decisions have been given is
8497.
Of these, 79% i.e. 6750 complaints were
fully accepted.  That means the company
accepted these complaints and whatever
money was earned or whatever decision was taken, it
went in favor of the policy holder.  8% of the
complaints were partially accepted.
Partially means
some amount was deducted with some conditions or
half the thing was accepted and half was not.  That means,
8% of the 100 complaints were partially
accepted and a total of 12.5% ​​i.e.
1062 complaints were completely rejected.
Now if you add both totally accepted and
partially accepted,
then out of 100, 87 almost 88% complaints were
completely accepted.   The
fully accepted rate was 80% and the
rejection rate was 12 1/2%.  What do we find out here
?  Now, first of all, it is quite
positive that after complaining, the
decision is going in favor of the policy holder.
But the most important thing we need to
notice here is that this decision should have already been
in favor of the policy holder.  That
means there has been some delay or negligence on the part of the insurance company.
Due to which the policy holder had to complain
and what are most of the complaints related to?
Related to the claim.  So it is obvious that the
decision on claim related complaints would also have
gone in favor of the policy holder.  That means the
claim money which should have been given directly to the police holders on time was
not given on time.  But when complaints were made on grievances,
almost 88% of the complaints
gave positive results.  Now friends,
after understanding the data of own damage claims of this latest motor insurance, two-three
important things come to light.  First of all,
if a big claim comes in the policies of United India, then it will take a
long time for the claim to be settled.
Because you saw that 20% of the total pending
claim amount has been pending for more than a year.
And see how troubled those policy holders will be.
Of the total outstanding claims, 10% are claims that
are pending for more than a year.  This means that there
may be a delay in receiving the claim, especially
if the amount is high. The second thing that
comes to light is that if the company is
troubling you in giving the claim or is
not listening to you or you feel that you should have
received the claim but the company did
not give the claim, then complain to the grievances.  The
total and partial
acceptance rate of complaints combined is 90%.  That means the
complaints of 90 out of 100 people were
accepted.  That means the decision
went in his favor.  And you already know this.
Proper records of any complaint you write on the Grievance Portal are maintained.
It has a turnaround time.  The company has to respond within 15 days
and the company
cannot adopt a makeshift approach there.
They must respond with a valid reason.
Because all these complaints
also remain in the notice of IRDA.  So friends, I
hope that after watching this video, if you buy any motor insurance policy of United India, be it
car, bike, taxi or commercial vehicle, then
you will
not be surprised if there is any delay in the claim
or you face any problem
and now you also know that a
solution can be found by complaining.  Along with this,
why do we buy policies of United India Insurance?
You should also know what are its advantages and disadvantages.
If you have had any particular experience
with United India's motor insurance policy, whether good
or bad, please
share it with me in the comments section so that we can spread
more awareness and information to other viewers as well.
If you liked and understood the video and information, then to
show your love and support,
please like the video and subscribe to the channel.  Because on Insurance Impact channel
you will find only such videos which are truly
useful for the policy holders.
I am Harvinder Singh, I will meet you
in the next video.  Till then take care,
stay fit and stay healthy.  Jai Hind.